Several Days After the Battle with the Dukedom of Dakia
The southern region reports that,
（レルゲン）
南方管区の報告では―
我が軍は 第７航空艦隊
による支援の下―
with the 7th Air Fleet's aid, we have
broken through the Dakian central lines.
戦線中央部の突破に成功
ダキア軍の連絡線を
寸断し制圧すべく―
We are now beginning a mop-up operation
掃討戦へ移行せり
とのことです
to cut the enemy's comms lines
and destroy them.
（ルーデルドルフ）
７万の兵で60万を蹂躙(じゅうりん)か
Overwhelming a force of 600,000
with only 70,000?
Splendid.
痛快だな
We should be able to occupy Dakia by winter.
（将校）この冬には
占領できそうですね
But our country still fights on two fronts.
（ゼートゥーア）とは言え
いまだ我が国では―
２つの戦線を
抱え込んだままだ
（レルゲン）
共和国および協商連合
The Republic and the Entente Alliance.
There's a lull in the fighting
in both theaters, but...
どちらの戦線も
小康状態を保っていますが
We are worrying about a world war.
（ルーデルドルフ）
世界大戦も
危惧される状況だ
The fewer fronts we must
fight on, the better.
戦線が少ないに
越したことはない
ダキア同様―
Our only choice is to start wiping out
the weaker enemies, like Dakia.
脆弱(ぜいじゃく)な敵から 率先して
たたくしかなかろう
We attack the Entente Alliance, then?
では 協商連合への攻勢を
They're probably more fragile
than the Republic.
共和国よりは もろかろう
問題は補給だ
The problem is supply.
Our supplies in the central Norden Region...
ノルデン地方の
兵站(へいたん)状況だが…
（ゼートゥーア）
攻勢の事前集積には―
I'd like a little time to stock
supplies before an assault.
今しばらく
時間をもらいたい
積雪のため―
The snow's slowing railway development.
野戦軽便鉄道の
敷設が遅れている
長いつきあいだ
はっきり言え
We've known each other a
long time. Out with it.
We're already taxing the northern rail
and port systems to their limits.
既に北方の鉄道部と港湾施設を
限界まで使っている
No dramatic change can be
effected in a short time.
短期で劇的に改善する
見込みは なしだ
Making it through winter is all we
can do with our current supplies.
（ゼートゥーア）
現在の備蓄状況では―
越冬が精いっぱいだ
We don't have any to spare for an offensive.
攻勢に必要な物資など
とても賄えん
I get that our current
supply lines have issues.
（ルーデルドルフ）
現有補給線に―
問題があることは
理解したが―
その上で
１つ考えがある
But I have a suggestion.
貴様の虎の子を
使わせてもらいたい
I would like to use your ace in the hole...
The 203rd Battalion,
which attacked the Dakian capital.
ダキアの首都を
襲撃した―
例の 二〇三大隊だ
Imperial Army Southeastern Theater, Military Garrison 5
（ヴァイス）
総員 傾注！
Attention!
Good work in Dakia, everyone.
（ターニャ）諸君
ダキアでの働きは ご苦労であった
As I'm sure you've already heard,
the 203rd has received a transfer order.
（ターニャ）
既に聞き及んでいると思うが
我々 第二〇三航空魔導大隊に
転属命令が出ている
We're heading north, to Norden.
北方ノルデン行きだ
（隊員）南の次は北か
（隊員）忙しいな
First the south, then the north.
No rest for the weary.
（隊員）
ちょうどいい スキーの気分だ
It's perfect. I've been wanting to ski.
We were always intended as
a rapid-response force,
もともと
即応の遊撃大隊ではあるが
参謀本部は我々を
馬車馬並みに こき使うらしい
but it looks like HQ wants to
work us like draft horses...
I'm sure they have quite the carrot for us.
さぞ大きなキャロットが
用意されているだろうな
But horses aren't lucky enough
to get food for free.
（ターニャ）とは言え
タダで飯が食えるほど―
馬という生物も恵まれてはおらん
参謀本部より指名だぞ
Strategic HQ specifically requested us.
Our opponent in this snowball fight is
雪合戦の お相手は―
無謀な領土侵犯を行ってきた
協商連合だ
the Triple Entente, which has launched
several attacks on our territory.
We're expected to test a new type of tactic.
我々には 新戦術の実戦検証が
期待されている
We have to show them that our battalion
has its act together enough for hiking.
ハイキングに行ける程度には―
団体行動ができることを
示さねばならん
Do not forget your duty as soldiers!
くれぐれも
軍人としての義務を忘れるな！
Yes, ma'am!
結構　ではこれより
参謀本部からの通達を告げる
Good...
We will now relay to you the orders from HQ.
Lieutenant Weiss.
ヴァイス中尉
At 1800, we will start the long,
overnight journey north.
（ヴァイス）本日18：00より
北方への夜間長距離進出を開始
（ヴィーシャ）少佐殿
ノルデンまでの飛行プランですが…
Major, about the flight plan to Norden...
Second Lieutenant Serebryakov,
don't you think it's strange?
（ターニャ）セレブリャコーフ少尉
おかしいと思わんか
（ヴィーシャ）
な… 何がでしょう？
Wh-What is?
中央軍が抜けたとはいえ
Even without the central forces,
国力差からして 協商連合軍には
勝利していて当然
we should be more than capable of
defeating the Entente Alliance.
That war should've been over by now.
本来 決着がついておらねばならん
（ヴィーシャ）うん？
（ターニャ）つまり誰かが―
That means someone is poking
their nose where it doesn't belong.
余計なおせっかいを
しているということだ
One of the other major
powers is intervening?
他の列強諸国が介入を？
Yeah.
The Republic... The Allied Kingdom...
共和国か 連合王国―
その両方かは知らんが…
Perhaps both.
But the whole world will be
watching as we go hiking.
我々は世界に のぞき見られながら
ハイキングを楽しむわけだ
（ヴィーシャ）分かりました
それとなく各員に伝えておきます
Understood.
I'll pass it on.
世界大戦は想定内だが
思った以上に動きが早い
I knew a world war was a possibility,
but things are moving faster than I expected.
突発的なダキアの侵攻も
不可解だったが
Dakia's sudden invasion was also inexplicable.
It's possible...
もしや…
That the insane, self-proclaimed "God"
is using his invisible hand here.
（ターニャ）
神を自称する理不尽な輩(やから)―
見えざる者の手が
働いているのかもな
Episode Six
Beginning of Madness
Entente Alliance Capital, Ministry of Defense
（カゾール）朗報だぞ 諸君
Excellent news, everyone.
It's still in the early stages,
Entente Alliance Council of Ten
Olvajoule Kazole
付け焼き刃ではあるが
but we've begun the process
of working with our allies.
一応 同盟国との
連携が始まった
That is good to hear.
（委員）
それは 結構なことですが―
我々が ダキアの二の舞になるのを
恐れているだけでは
But aren't they afraid that
we'll end up like Dakia?
（委員）我が国が破れ―
They're afraid that we'll fall,
帝国の国力が
共和国戦に投じられる危惧とは…
and then the Empire can direct
its full force toward the Republic.
That news makes us sound pitiful.
惨めな気分になる知らせですなあ
Not only the Republic,
but the Allied Kingdom will aid us, too.
共和国に限らず 連合王国も
援助をしてくれるそうだ
内々だが 既に帝国軍の監視も
始められているらしい
They've also begun secretly
monitoring the Empire.
I'm envious they have resources to spare.
（委員）国力に余裕がある国は
うらやましいな
We have nothing left to spare at all.
我々には 余力など
もう どこにもないというのに
We're forced to ask the other
major powers for aid.
（カゾール）諸列強の介入頼み
It's pathetic,
情けないかぎりだが
我々には他に選択肢がない
but we have few other options.
Thus, let us do the best we can now.
ならば 今できる最善を尽くそう
Imperial Army, Northern Region Kraggana Supply Base
Fire! Fire! Fire!
（大隊長）撃て 撃て 撃てー！
Keep firing!
（大隊長）射撃を絶やすな！
Damn it, they got here
faster than expected!
クソッ 想定より早すぎるぞ！
（中尉）数も予想以上です
There are more of them, too.
Those intelligence asses said we
had nothing to worry about.
情報部め！
何が“大したことはない”だ
I'm running out of magical energy...
（隊員）もう残存魔力が限界です
（隊員）
防殻術式も ままなりません！
I can't keep up my defensive spells!
Battalion Commander, let's fall back.
大隊長！
ここは一旦 さがりましょう
ダメだ！ 集積地を何としても
死守せねば…
No!
We have to defend
the supply base to the death...
グハッ！
Battalion Commander!
（中尉）大隊長ー！
I screwed up...
抜かった
すまん… あとは任せる
I'm sorry. Take care of the rest...
Roger.
了解です
03 07 貴様らも限界だ
大隊長殿と後退しろ！
03 and 07, you're at your limits, too.
Take the commander and fall back.
This is Viper 02.
（中尉）こちら ヴァイパー02
大隊長 負傷につき
The commander has been wounded,
and I'm assuming command.
指揮権を継承する
Roger, Viper 02.
（通信兵）了解 ヴァイパー02
それと悪い知らせだ
And I've got bad news.
Emergency message from
the northeast area.
北東エリアより急報
Observation teams have spotted
two company-sized units of mages.
２個中隊規模の敵魔導部隊を
観測班が目視した
Additional forces?
（中尉）増援!?
連中のどこに そんな余力が…
Where were they hiding until now?
We've confirmed foreign mages
of unknown nationality.
（通信兵）国籍不明の
義勇軍魔導師の混在を確認
They'll be in your airspace soon.
認知圏内への接近は確実の見込み
It will be very hard to fight further.
これ以上の迎撃は困難だ
即時 後退の許可を！
Requesting permission to withdraw!
Lieutenant, multiple sightings at two o'clock.
（隊員）
中尉殿！ ２時方向に機影多数
爆撃機です
Bombers...
Contact lost with forward units!
（隊員）前衛との通信 途絶！
M-Multiple bombers sighted.
ば… 爆撃機を複数確認
直ちに要撃機部隊を出撃されたし！
Send interceptors immediately!
（通信兵）５分待て
司令部と検討する 迎撃は可能か？
Wait five minutes.
We'll discuss it with command.
Can you intercept?
ふざけるな！ 高度が違いすぎる！
Hell no!
Our altitudes are too different.
敵魔導部隊も排除できてない！
And we haven't wiped out
the enemy mages!
That base holds mountains of our supplies.
（通信兵）集積地には
備蓄の物資が山積みだ
If it's bombed, we won't last the winter.
爆撃されたら 冬が越せなくなる
Please... Just hang in there.
頼む！ 持ちこたえろ
Bombers are at an altitude over 9,000.
爆撃機は 高度9,000以上だぞ
Only fighters can go that high.
戦闘機でないかぎり
迎撃は不可能だ
うう… ダメだ！
このままでは もう…
Not good.
We'll be wiped out!
（通信兵）何？ 本当か！
What? Is that true?
よし… ヴァイパー大隊
直ちに後退せよ！ 後退せよ！
All right! Viper Battalion, retreat at once!
Retreat!
Reinforcements from central!
中央からの援軍だ
大隊規模で エリアＢ３より急行中
Battalion-sized unit
heading your way from area B-3!
コールサインは“ピクシー”
Their call sign is "Pixie"!
喜べ！
指揮官は“ネームド”だぞ！
Rejoice! Their commander is a named mage!
Enemy mage unit at altitude 6,500.
（ヴィーシャ）
敵魔導部隊は高度6,500
Forward forces are regiment-sized.
前衛は 準連隊規模
後衛は ２個中隊です
Two companies to the rear.
Companies 2 through 4 will
hit the forward units.
（ターニャ）
第２から第４中隊は前衛に当たれ
We'll take out the rear units and bombers.
我々は後衛および爆撃機をたたく
その後 背後より挟撃だ
Then we'll launch a pincer
attack from the rear.
ただし 諸君らのノルマは
足止めだが―
However, while your job is to delay them,
別に私を待つ必要はないぞ
there isn't any need to wait for me.
Feel free to defeat them all.
全て倒してしまっても
一向にかまわん
Yes, ma'am!
さて 第１中隊諸君 高度を上げろ
Now, Company 1, gain altitude.
We'll go around and knock out
the two rear companies.
迂回(うかい)して
後衛の２個中隊をたたくぞ
Imperial Army, Northern Theater Command
Northern Theater Strategic Commander
Lieutenant General Heinrich Schreise
Interceptors are ready to go whenever, yes?
（シュライゼ）要撃機は
いつでも上がれるのだな
Yes, they're standing by in the hangars.
（将校）
はっ 格納庫にて待機中です
命令がありしだい
すぐに出せますが
Ready to launch on your order.
Let's do it, then.
では 出すべきだろう
爆撃機の侵入は阻止せねば
We need to stop those bombers.
（通信兵）
二〇三航空魔導大隊より入電！
Message from the 203rd Battalion,
Pixie Battalion, the ones fighting.
（通信兵）
出撃中のピクシー大隊です
What?
何？ 読み上げろ
Read it.
それが… えーと…
Well, um...
What is it? Hurry up!
何だ 早くしろ！
“手出し ご無用”と…
They say they don't need help...
“手出し ご無用”？
They don't need help?
They've got guts, huh?
ハッ いい度胸だ！
我々に恩を売るつもりか
They want us to owe them a favor.
Airborne Control has sighted Pixie Battalion.
（通信兵）
管制機 ピクシー大隊を確認
速度250 高度…
Speed is 250.
Altitude is...
随分と速いな…
ん？ 高度はどうした？
Pretty fast.
What's their altitude?
（通信兵）こ… 高度7,500…
いえ なお上昇中であります！
A-Altitude is 7,500...
No, it's still increasing!
何だと!?
What?
It must be some mistake.
何かの間違いだろう
戦闘機ではないのだぞ
Those are mages, not fighter planes.
They're certain. Present altitude is 8,500.
（通信兵）間違いありません
現在 高度8,500 速度300！
Speed is 300!
Is their gear working?
機械は正常なのか？
They're working fine.
異常は見られません 全て正常です
Everything is working properly.
I can't believe it.
信じられん…
It seems Strategic HQ had an
unexpected ace up its sleeve.
参謀本部は 規格外の切り札を
持っているようだな
（ノイマン）えいっ！
近接戦 用意！
敵前衛を排除するぞ！
Prepare for close-quarters combat!
We'll wipe out the enemy's forward units!
（ケーニッヒ）チッ
敵の演算宝珠は予想以上に高性能だ
The enemy's computation jewels
are better than expected.
Don't get cocky!
侮るなよ！
They're fast.
チッ 速い！
They can hit accurately with
this altitude difference?
この高低差で当ててくるか
Seems like it's those foreign mages.
（グランツ）
例の義勇軍魔導師のもようです
They're tougher than we'd thought.
（ヴァイス）
思ったより手ごわいな
So, everyone, how are you
enjoying a real war?
（ターニャ）
さて諸君 本物の戦争はどうだ？
The other day's battle against Dakia
was just a live-fire exercise.
先日のダキア戦は
あくまでも実弾演習
今回は戦意旺盛な諸君のため
援軍は丁重にお断りしておいた
I want to let you fight
to your heart's content this time,
so I turned down reinforcements.
Be proud. You've been given a chance
to pass a trial of iron and fire.
火と鉄の試練をくぐる機会が
与えられたと誇りたまえ
Our battle is being watched
by the other major powers
我々の戦いは 他の列強諸国
ひいては世界にのぞき見られている
and the entire world.
Our nation's honor is at stake,
and failure isn't permitted!
国威のためにも 失敗は許されん
That's just like the major...
まったく… 少佐殿らしいな
Also, the company that contributes least
なお 帰還後の祝賀会は
一番成績の悪い中隊のおごりとする
will pay for the post-victory celebration.
I ordered some fine
twenty-five-year-old booze.
25年物を発注しておいた
破産したくなければ奮闘するように
If you don't want to go bankrupt, fight hard.
Company 2, maximum altitude!
第２中隊 最高高度だ！
Everyone, fly like death's at your heels!
各員 死ぬ気で飛べー！
Don't bankrupt me!
俺を破産させるなよ！
各中隊 奮戦しています！
All companies are fighting hard.
（ターニャ）
フンッ 有能な指揮官ぶりを―
It's hard to show off how good
a commander you are.
アピールするのも
難しいものだな… んっ
It's them! The bombers!
（ヴィーシャ）
来ました 爆撃機です！
They're finally here, huh?
ようやく お出ましか…
Enemy mage company below us.
（敵兵）
眼下に敵魔導中隊を確認
（敵兵）敵影12
高度6,500 どうしますか？
Twelve of them. Altitude 6,500.
What do we do?
（編隊長）
護衛の魔導部隊に任せておけ
Leave them to the rear mage units.
この高度差だ
下からではどうにもならん
We're too high up for them to do anything.
敵の直掩(ちょくえん)も来ました
２個中隊の敵魔導師です
Enemy escorts are here, too.
Two mage companies.
Second Lieutenant, lead the
company and take them out.
少尉 隊を率いて迎撃しろ
悪いが 私はあれを独り占めだ
Sorry, but I'm taking all those for myself.
あ… あの数の爆撃機ですよ？
A-All those bombers?
I actually want to become the air force's
ace, too, and this is my big chance.
実は 空軍でもエースになりたいと
思っていたところでな
（ヴィーシャ）それには 戦闘機で
落とす必要がありますけど…
I'm afraid you'd need to do it in a plane
to stand any chance, ma'am.
そうなのか？
だったら 取りに戻りたいくらいだ
Really?
I wish I could go back and get one, then.
But I guess I can't turn
my back on them now.
（ターニャ）とは言え
この状況で背を向けるのは無理か
Don't want them thinking I retreated
when I faced the enemy.
敵前逃亡扱いされては かなわん
給料分の仕事はするとしよう
Guess I'll work enough to earn my salary.
Company 1, we're advancing!
（ヴィーシャ）
第１中隊！ 前へ出るぞ！
（敵兵）うん？
い… １体 来ます！
O-One mage incoming!
One mage?
１体？ バカな！ 自殺行為だぞ！
Impossible!
That's suicide.
S-Speed is 250.
そ… 速度250 高度7,500！
Altitude is 7,500.
何だと!?
What?
（敵兵）まだ上昇中です！
They're still climbing!
（ターニャ）お相手は鈍重な鉄の塊
ダンスを踊れるとは思えんな
I'm up against some slow,
heavy chunks of steel.
I won't be able to dance with them.
（敵兵）高度8,000… 8,500！
このままでは並ばれます！
Altitude 8,000... 8,500.
At this rate, she'll match us!
高度をとるぞ！
各機 弾幕を張れ！
Climb!
Everyone, lay down some fire!
（敵兵）速すぎる！
She's too fast!
この時ばかりは
小さな体に感謝するよ
It's only times like this when
I'm happy to have this tiny body.
A-Altitude is 10,000!
（敵兵）こ… 高度１万！
（編隊長）何なんだ こいつは！
Who is this girl?
Damn it... Hit her! Hit her!
（敵兵）
クソッ 当たれ！ 当たれー！
（敵兵）やめろ 下手に撃つな！
落ち着いて狙いを… あっ…
Stop.
Don't fire randomly!
Calm down and aim—
Good day, gentlemen.
（ターニャ）こんにちは
And goodbye.
そして… さようなら
（敵兵）へ… 編隊長機が！
The formation leader's plane...
（敵兵）
さ… 作戦中止だ！ 急速旋回！
C-Call off the mission!
Turn around, fast!
爆弾を投棄だ！ 機体を軽くしろ！
Release all bombs and lighten the planes!
ハァ… 固定砲台並みの
単純作業だな
This is as easy as hitting
fixed-gun emplacements.
主よ 我が祈りを聞き
我が願いに耳を傾けよ
Lord, hear my prayer,
and grant my desire.
Bring down the hammer of
your wrath from Heaven.
天上の世界から鉄槌(てっつい)を下したまえ
（敵兵）
メーデー！ メーデー！ こちら…
Mayday! Mayday!
This is—
Pixie 01 to all units.
ピクシー01より各部隊へ
The metal birds are
heading back to their nest.
機械の鳥たちは
ねぐらに帰るようだ
諸君は 残存魔導師の
挟撃を開始しろ
Begin your pincer attack
on the remaining mages.
I'm going to recover prisoners
from the prey I shot down.
私は落とした獲物
捕虜の回収に向かう
I wanted to get some information from them,
情報を
聞き出したかったんだが
脳みそを拾って
帰るわけにもいかんしなあ
but I can't just cut out their brain and take it.
It's a joyous thing.
（存在Ｘ(エックス)）喜ばしいことだ
（存在Ｘ）この世界の誰もが―
Everyone in this world is out for
your blood, you of so little faith.
信仰なき貴様を
葬らんとしている
A great crusade to punish
the blasphemer has begun.
冒とく者を罰する聖なる大戦が
幕を開けたのだ
存在Ｘ…
やはり貴様が おせっかいを！
Being X...
I knew you were screwing with me!
How does it feel to fight the entire world?
（存在Ｘ）どうかね？ 世界を
相手に無謀な戦いを挑む気分は
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
Damn it!
クソッ ふざけるな！
I'll show you!
Somewhere in the Norden Region, Allied Kingdom Army Observation Post
It's the named mage we saw in the west.
（観測兵）やはり西方で確認された
ネームドに間違いありません
個体照合 “ラインの悪魔”です
We've identified her. The Devil of the Rhine.
So she's real?
（ドレイク）
実在したのか
Allied Kingdom Army Military Intelligence
Lieutenant Colonel Sir Isaac Dustin Drake
I guess the Republican forces
weren't dreaming.
共和国の連中
白昼夢を見ていたわけでは
ないらしいな
We were right to put an observation
system quickly into place.
早急に監視体制を整えていて
正解だったな
She took out those bombers by herself.
単独で爆撃機を撃退するなど
まさしく悪魔だ
She really is a devil.
You have the recorded data, right?
記録データはとれているな
（観測兵）はっ 問題ありません
Yes, no problem.
（ドレイク）通信の傍受はどうだ？
（観測兵）残念ながら…
What about communications intercept?
Unfortunately, they used an unknown
encryption algorithm...
未知の暗号による
通信形式でしたので
（ドレイク）
管制機を上げたいところだが―
I'd love to put up a control plane,
but our priority now is taking
this equipment back, huh?
今は機材を持って帰るほうが先決か
（観測兵）
あ… アルファ大隊からです
It's from Alpha Unit.
The named is emitting a powerful
magical-energy signal.
“ネームドより
高魔力反応を察知した”と
Your light is like the morning sun.
（ターニャ）
朝日のごとく御光をもて
よし いいデータをとるチャンスだ
All right.
This is our chance for good data.
Use it to illuminate the darkness,
hidden in the ground.
（ターニャ）
土に隠れし暗きを照らせ
What is she doing?
一体 何をするつもりだ
（観測兵）さあな 見当もつかん
I can't even imagine.
あっ き… 機材の電源を落とせ！
逆探されている！
Turn off power to the equipment!
She's tracked us back!
（ターニャ）
今ぞ生まれし主をたたえよ
Praise the Lord, who is now born unto us!
I-I've detected an artillery spell!
ほ… 砲撃術式を感知！
Does she realize how far away she is?
（観測兵）
どれだけ距離があると思っている！
Retreat... Retreat!
退避… 退避ー！
Observation waves are gone.
（ヴィーシャ）観測波の消滅を確認
Splendid work, Major.
お見事です！ 少佐殿
少佐殿… 何か？
Major... is something wrong?
Let's go. We'll wipe out
the remaining enemies.
（ターニャ）行くぞ 残敵掃討だ
Damn it! She got us!
クソッ やってくれる…
Republican Capital Parisee, Ministry of Defense
The Entente Alliance's attack
on the supply depot has failed.
（ビアント）協商連合軍は
集積地の襲撃に失敗
Republican Army 2nd Mage Company
Lieutenant Colonel Zevran Biantot
The mages we sent suffered
multiple casualties.
我が軍が派遣した
魔導師にも―
多数の損害が
出ているもようです
Vice Minister of Defense and Armies
General Pierre Michelaud Lugo
Message to Entente Alliance Command.
協商連合軍の司令部へ
ダキア戦を分析した結果として―
We've told you that an analysis
of the attack on Dakia
後方地帯が手薄では
危うい旨を伝えていますが
reveals that leaving your rear lines
undefended is dangerous."
They're in bad shape.
あのような窮状です
かの国には
期待するだけ無駄なのでは
Don't you think expecting anything
from them is pointless?
（ド･ルーゴ）
口を慎め ビアント中佐
Silence, Colonel Biantot.
I-I'm sorry!
し… 失礼しました
Doomed or not, we'll use what we can.
（ド･ルーゴ）たとえ泥舟だろうと
使えるものは使う
Naturally.
当然だ
Imperial Army, Northern Theater Forces Command
Welcome to Norden.
（ルーデルドルフ）
ようこそ ノルデンへ
Or should I say welcome back,
Major Degurechaff?
いや… おかえりと言うべきかな
デグレチャフ少佐
Yes, I've returned to the battlefield here,
はっ 懐かしの戦場に
帰ってまいりました
General Rudersdorf.
ルーデルドルフ閣下
Glad to have you.
（ルーデルドルフ）ご苦労！
That was splendid work today.
早速だが 見事なものだったと
言わせてくれ
I'm honored, General.
光栄であります 閣下
I'd like to give you plenty of
opportunities to fight here.
こちらでも存分に暴れてもらいたい
Yes, sir.
Excellent.
結構
All right, let's start talking about work.
では 仕事の話に入るが…
Major, you will be taking out an
enemy defensive placement.
少佐 貴官の部隊には
敵防御陣地を
制圧してもらうことになる
それは前線の押し上げという
ことでありましょうか
Does that mean we're
advancing the front lines?
With our present supply situation...
現状の兵站状況では とても…
For now, I'll merely say it is a new plan.
今のところ 新たな作戦とだけ
言っておこう
Roger.
了解いたしました
As you know, the other major powers
are beginning to intervene.
（ルーデルドルフ）知ってのとおり
列強の介入が始まった
いよいよ 厄介事(やっかいごと)も増えるが―
We'll have a real mess on our hands.
But we're counting on you, Major.
期待しているぞ 少佐
（存在Ｘ）どうかね？ 世界を
相手に無謀な戦いを挑む気分は
How does it feel to fight the entire world?
Yes, sir.
（ターニャ）
はっ 協商連合のみならず
Not only the Entente Alliance,
but the Republic and the Allied Kingdom...
共和国に連合王国 そして
おせっかいな連中 全てに
And anyone else who wants to meddle...
I'll teach them all a lesson.
目に物見せてやります
Hallway, Entente Alliance Ministry of Defense
5th Air Mage Battalion
Colonel Anson Sue
Colonel...
（グンナー）大佐殿
Congratulations on your promotion.
（グンナー）
改めて 昇進おめでとうございます
Don't be stupid.
（アンソン）バカを言え
You can tell where our country's headed
by the fact that I was promoted
戦死した上官の穴埋めで
昇進するなど
because my superior officer was killed.
我が国の未来は 推して知るべしだ
If you survive till next year,
you'll be a general.
（グンナー）
来年まで生きてれば 将官
If you survive two years, you might
be running the whole place.
再来年なら
元帥も夢ではありませんね
（アンソン）フンッ
軽口をたたく暇があったら―
If you have time for jokes, get ready to go.
出発準備を整えろ 後方行きだぞ
We're heading to the rear lines.
Yes, sir.
はっ 大変失礼しました
I'm terribly sorry, sir.
（ターニャ）
ヴァイス中尉は すばらしいな
You impress me, Lieutenant Weiss.
（ヴァイス）
ど… どうされたんですか？ 突然
Wh-Where's this coming from?
（ターニャ）
貴官は タバコを吸わんだろう
You don't smoke, right?
個人の権利を
制限する気はないし―
I have no intention of restricting any rights,
and I don't want to tell people
not to smoke on the battlefield.
戦場での喫煙を
否定しようとも思わんが―
せめて分煙を
要求したいところだな
But I wish people would keep
the secondhand smoke in mind.
（ヴァイス）分煙？ 分煙とは…
Secondhand smoke?
What's that?
第二〇三航空魔導大隊
ターニャ･デグレチャフ少佐だ
Major Tanya Degurechaff,
with the 203rd Air Mage Battalion.
This way.
（衛兵）こちらへ
Next Episode
War Report
This program is fiction.
All persons, groups, places, laws,
and names appearing in it have
no relation to the real world.